GURJEET SINGH

Hayes, London

Phone: 07740093490 | Email: gsgghotra@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/gsgghotra/ | GitHub: github.com/gsgghotra

Portfolio: https://portfolio-gurjeet.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

Front-End Web Developer and Computer Science graduate specialising in Advanced Web Development with Big Data. Currently pursuing a front-end web development bootcamp to stay at the forefront of industry trends and technologies. A strong commitment to effective communication, collaboration, and teamwork, honed during teaching experience, underpins the ability to craft visually engaging websites while also prioritising an exceptional user experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: ReactJS, Angular, Javascript ES6+, Typescript, HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap, SASS

Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, NodeJs, Firebase

Skills and Abilities: Git Source Control, Cl /CD - Github, Agile Methodology

PROJECTS

SNEAKERSTREETS github.com/gsgghotra/SneakerStreets sneakerstreets.netlify.app

SneakerStreets is an innovative eCommerce platform dedicated to providing sneaker enthusiasts with a seamless shopping experience to acquire their favorite footwear.

- Contributed as ReactJs and Javascript developer and implemented basket and search features.
- ReactJs, JavaScript, React Redux, NodeJs, NPM, Vite, Bootstrap, Tailwind

HarmonyHeal | github.com/gsgghotra/HarmonyHeal | https://gsgghotra.github.io/HarmonyHeal/ HarmonyHeal is the ultimate music meditation app designed to bring tranquility and enhance your well-being.

- Contributed as Javascript developer and implemented Spotify API in the web app.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, RESTful API, Bootstrap

Price Comparison Web App | github.com/gsqqhotra/iPhones-price-finder | https://bit.ly/pricescrape

Created a real-time iPhone price comparison web app that scrape data from five different websites,

created a real-time iPhone price comparison web app that scrape data from five different websites, enabling users to quickly find the lowest-priced iPhone and access direct product links.

- Deployed the web app to AWS using services such as **EC2**, **RDS** & **S3** to ensure high availability.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, RESTful API, MySQL, Java, Maven

EDUCATION

Front-End Web Development Bootcamp Certificate: edX

Sep 2023 - Current

An intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express and ReactJS. Focused on working collaboratively with colleagues to successfully plan and execute projects, ensuring timely completion and delivering high-quality results.

Computing PGCE (Postgraduate Certificate in Education): University College London, UK **June 2023**Two Work placements along with Two Master Level Modules: Subject Studies and Professional Practice.
Developed an e-learning platform to help the computer-science department with resources.

Degree or Certification: Pass

Computer Science BSc: Middlesex University, UK

June 2021

Final Year Modules include Advanced Web Development with Big Data, Novel Interaction Technologies, User Experience (UX) Design and Undergraduate Individual Project.

Degree or Certification: First Class Honours

EXPERIENCE

Computer Science Trainee Teacher (work placement)

Feb 2023 - June 2023

Ruislip High School

Southall, London, UK

- Collaborated with the Computer Science department to deliver high-quality education to students from Year 7 to Year 13, showcasing effective teamwork and communication skills.
- Enhanced departmental goals with an adaptive e-resource website, creating a more inclusive and accessible learning environment, elevating student experiences.

Computer Science Trainee Teacher (work placement)

Sep 2022 - Feb 2023

Villiers High School

Southall, London, UK

- Designed curriculum units and learning materials for multiple year groups, highlighting strong collaboration and effective communication within the department.
- Initiated girls-only coding club after revealing a gender participation gap through school research, promoting inclusivity and engagement.

IT Support Technician

Sep 2021 - July 2022

Greenford High School

Provided essential first-line desktop support, effectively resolving technical issues, overseeing critical incidents, and managing diverse service requests.

- Efficiently set up and maintained computer labs, ensuring staff and students had uninterrupted access to essential software and resources, enhancing the user experience.
- Demonstrated a strong ability to prioritise, diagnose, and efficiently resolve incidents, following agreed-upon procedures to minimise downtime and disruptions.